这玩意开着的吗？
Is this thing on?
让我们播放一段跟星球大战电影一样的开场字幕吧 第二集开始了！
Cue the epic Star Wars crawl, and, action.
OS 战争第二部分：Linux 的崛起
Episode Two: Rise of Linux®.
微软帝国控制着 90％ 的用桌面用户
The empire of Microsoft controls 90 % of desktop users.
操作系统的完全标准化似乎是板上钉钉的事了
Complete standardization of operating systems seems assured.
所以公司们把它们的注意力从桌面端的个人用户 转移到了专业人士上
However, the advent of the internet swerves the focus of the war from the desktop toward enterprise,
它们为了服务器的所有权打得不可开交
where all businesses scramble to claim a server of their own.
但是一个有点让人意想不到的英雄出现在开源“反叛组织”中
Meanwhile, an unlikely hero arises from amongst the band of open source rebels .
戴着眼镜 固执的林纳斯·托瓦兹免费发布了他的 Linux® 程序
Linus Torvalds, head strong, bespectacled, releases his Linux system free of charge.
微软摔了个趔趄 并且开始重新调整战略
Microsoft reels — and regroups.
哦 我们极客们就是喜欢那样
Oh, the nerd in me just loves that.
上一次我们讲到哪了？
So, where were we?
苹果和微软互相攻伐
Apple and Microsoft were trading blows,
试图在争夺桌面用户的战争中占据主导地位
trying to dominate in a war over desktop users.
在第一集的结尾 我们看到微软获得了大部分的市场份额
By the end of episode one, we saw Microsoft claiming most of the prize.
很快 互联网的兴起以及随之而来的开发者大军
Soon, the entire landscape went through a seismic upheaval.
让整个市场都经历了一场地震
That's all because of the rise of the internet and the army of developers that rose with it.
互联网将战场从在家庭和办公室中的个人电脑用户
So the internet moves the battlefield from PC users in their home offices
转移到拥有数百台服务器的大型商业客户中
to giant business clients with hundreds of servers.
这意味着巨量资源的迁移
This is a huge resource shift.
突然间 所有相关企业不仅被迫为服务器空间和网站建设付费
Not only does every company out there wanting to remain relevant suddenly have to pay for server space and get a website built
还必须集成软件来进行资源跟踪和数据库监控等工作
they also have to integrate software to track resources, monitor databases, et cetera, et cetera.
至少那时候大家都是这么做的 你需要很多开发人员来帮助你
You're going to need a lot of developers to help you with that. At least, back then you did.
在操作系统之战的第二部分 我们将看到固有优势的巨大转变
In part two of the OS wars, we'll see how that enormous shift in priorities,
以及像林纳斯·托瓦兹和理查德·斯托尔曼这样的开源反叛者
and the work of a few open source rebels like Linus Torvalds and Richard Stallman,
是如何成功地在微软和整个软件行业的核心引发恐惧的
managed to strike fear in the heart of Microsoft, and an entire software industry.
我是 Saron Yitbarek 你现在收听的是代码英雄 一款红帽公司原创的播客节目
I'm Saron Yitbarek and you're listening to Command Line Heroes, an original podcast from Red Hat.
每一集 我们都会给你带来“从码开始” 用技术改变科技的人 他们的故事
In each episode, we're bringing you stories about the people who transform technology from the command line up.
好 想象一下你是 1991 年时的微软
Okay. Imagine for a second that you're Microsoft in 1991.
你自我感觉良好 对吧？
You're feeling pretty good, right?
你满怀信心 确立了全球主导地位的感觉真不错
Pretty confident. Assured global domination feels nice.
你已经掌握了与其他企业合作的艺术
You've mastered the art of partnering with other businesses,
但是仍然将大部分开发人员、程序员和系统管理员排除在联盟之外
but you're still pretty much cutting out the developers, programmers, and sys admins
而他们才是真正的武装力量
that are the real foot soldiers out there.
这时出现了一个叫林纳斯·托瓦兹的芬兰极客
There is this Finnish geek named Linus Torvalds.
他和一帮信奉开源的程序员开始发布 Linux
He and his team of open source programmers are starting to put out versions of Linux,
这个操作系统内核是由他们一起编写出来的
this OS kernel that they're duct taping together.
坦白地说 如果你是微软公司
If you're Microsoft,
你并不会太在意 Linux 甚至不太关心开源运动
frankly, you're not too concerned about Linux or even about open source in general,
但是最终 Linux 的规模变得如此之大
but eventually, the sheer size of Linux gets so big
以至于微软不可能不注意到
that it becomes impossible for Microsoft not to notice.
Linux 第一个版本出现在 1991 年 当时大概有 1 万行代码
The first version comes out in 1991 and it's got maybe 10,000 lines of code.
十年后 则是 300 万行代码
A decade later, there will be three million lines of code.
如果你想了解知道现在的 Linux 怎么样了 - 它有 2000 万行代码
And in case you're wondering, today it's at 20 million.
让我们在 90 年代初停留一会儿
For a moment, let's stay in the early 90s.
那时 Linux 还没有成为我们现在所知道的庞然大物
Linux hasn't yet become the behemoth we know now.
这只是一个正在蔓延的 拥有病毒一般感染力的奇怪操作系统
and the geeks and hackers of the world are falling in love with it.
不过全世界的极客和黑客都爱上了它
那时候我还太年轻 但有点希望我曾经历过那个年代
I was too young in those early days, but I sort of wish I'd been there.
我是说在那个时候 发现 Linux 就如同进入了一个秘密结社
I mean at that time,discovering Linux was like gaining access to a secret society.
程序员与朋友们分享刻录的 Linux CD 集
Programmers would share the Linux CD set with friends the same way other people would share mixtapes of underground music.
就像其他人分享地下音乐混音带一样
the same way other people would share mixtapes of underground music.
开发者 Tristram Oaten 讲讲你 16 岁时第一次接触 Linux 的故事吧
Developer Tristram Oaten tells the story of how he first encountered Linux when he was 16 years old.
我和我的家人去了红海的 Hurghada 潜水度假
We went on a scuba diving holiday, my family and I, to Hurghada, which is on the Red Sea.
那是一个美丽的地方 强烈推荐
Beautiful place, highly recommend it.
也许我妈妈跟我说过不要这么做 但第一天 我还是喝了自来水
The first day, I drank the tap water. Probably, my mom told me not to.
所以我整个星期都病得很厉害 没法离开旅馆房间
So I was really sick the whole week — didn't leave the hotel room.
当时我只带了一台新安装了 Slackware Linux 的笔记本电脑
All I had with me was a laptop with a fresh install of Slackware Linux,
我只是听说过这玩意 现在却要尝试使用它
this thing that I'd heard about and was giving it a try.
我手上没有其他的应用程序
There were no extra apps,
我能接触的所有东西只有刻录在 8 张 CD 上的代码
just what came on the eight CDs.
这种情况下 我整个星期能做的事情
By necessity, all I had to do this whole week
就是了解这个外星造物一般的系统
was to get to grips with this alien system.
我阅读手册 摆弄着终端
I read man pages, played around with the terminal.
我记得当时我甚至不知道“.”和“..”之间的区别
I remember not knowing the difference between a single dot, meaning the current directory, and two dots, meaning the previous directory.
我一点头绪都没有 犯过很多错误
I had no clue. I must have made so many mistakes,
但慢慢的 在这种被迫造成的孤独中
but slowly, over the course of this forcible solitude,
我突破了障碍 开始明白并理解命令行到底是怎么回事
I broke through this barrier and started to understand and figure out what this command line thing was all about.
假期结束时 我没有看过金字塔、尼罗河等任何埃及遗址
By the end of the holiday, I hadn't seen the pyramids, the Nile, or any Egyptian sites,
但我解锁了现代世界的一个奇迹
but I had unlocked one of the wonders of the modern world.
我接触了 Linux 接下来的事大家都知道了
I'd unlocked Linux, and the rest is history.
你会从很多人那里听到关于这个故事的不同版本
You can hear some variation on that story from a lot of people.
访问 Linux 命令行是一种革命性的体验
Getting access to that Linux command line was a transformative experience.
它提供了源代码 我当时的感觉是 “太神奇了 ”
This thing gave me the source code. I was like, "That's amazing."
我们正在参加一个名为 Flock to Fedora 的 2017 年 Linux 开发者大会
We're at a 2017 Linux developers conference called Flock to Fedora.
…非常有吸引力
... very appealing.
我觉得随着我掌控这个系统越深 它就越吸引我
I felt like I had more control over the system and it just drew me in more and more.
我想 从 1995 年我第一次编译 Linux 内核那时起 我就迷上了它
So,From there, I guess, after my first Linux kernel compile in 1995, I was hooked, so, yeah.
这是开发者 David Cantrell 与 Joe Brockmire
Developers David Cantrell and Joe Brockmire.
我在 Cheap Software 转的时候发现了一套四张 CD 的 Slackware Linux
I was going through the cheap software and found a four - CD set of Slackware Linux.
它看起来会非常令人兴奋而且很有趣 所以我把它带回家
And it sounded really exciting and interesting so I took it home,
安装在我的第二台电脑上 开始摆弄它
and installed it on a second computer, started playing with it,
有两件事情让我感到很兴奋：
and really got excited about two things.
一个是我运行的不是 Windows
One was, I was excited not to be running Windows,
另一个是 Linux 的开源特性
and I was excited by the open source nature of Linux.
某种程度上来说 使用命令行的人总是存在的
That access to the command line was, in some ways, always there.
在开源真正开始流行起来的二十年前
Decades before open source really took off,
人们总是希望能够做到完全控制机器
there was always a desire to have complete control,
至少…对于开发者来说是这样的
at least among developers.
让我们回到操作系统大战之前的那个时代
Go way back to a time before the OS wars,
在苹果和微软为他们的 GUI 而战之前
before Apple and Microsoft were fighting over their GUIs.
那时也有代码英雄
There were command line heroes then, too.
保罗·琼斯教授（在线图书馆 ibiblio.org 的负责人）
Paul Jones is the director of the online library ibiblio.org.
就是一名那个古老年代的开发人员
He worked as a developer during those early days.
从本质上讲 互联网在那个时候客户端-服务器架构还是比较少的
The internet, by its nature, at that time, was less client server,
而更多的是点对点架构的
totally, and more peer to peer.
确实 我们会说 某种 VAX 到 VAX 的连接
We're talking about, really, some sort of VAX to VAX,
某种科学工作站到科学工作站的连接
some sort of scientific workstation, the scientific workstation.
这并不意味着没有客户端-服务端的架构及应用程序
That doesn't mean that client and server relationships and applications weren't there,
但这的确意味着 最初的设计是思考如何实现点对点
but it does mean that the original design was to think of how to do peer - to - peer things,
它与 IBM 一直在做的东西相对立
the opposite of what IBM had been doing,
IBM 给你的只有哑终端 这种终端只能让你管理用户界面
in which they had dumb terminals that had only enough intelligence to manage the user interface,
却无法让你像真正的终端一样为所欲为
but not enough intelligence to actually let you do anything in the terminal that would expose anything to it.
当图形用户界面在普通用户中普及的同时
As popular as GUI was becoming among casual users,
在工程师和开发人员中总是存在着一股相反的力量
there was always a pull in the opposite direction for the engineers and developers.
早在 Linux 出现之前的二十世纪七八十年代
Before Linux in the 1970s and 80s,
这股力量就存在于 Emacs 和 GNU 中
that resistance was there, with EMACS and GNU.
斯托曼的自由软件基金会中的某些人想要使用完全命令行
W th Stallman's free software foundation, certain folks were always begging for access to the command line,
但直到上世纪 90 年代的 Linux 出现 才提供了前所未有的东西
but it was Linux in the 1990s that delivered like no other.
Linux 和其他开源软件的早期爱好者是都是先驱
The early lovers of Linux and other open source software were pioneers.
我正站在他们的肩膀上 我们都是
I'm standing on their shoulders. We all are.
你现在收听的是代码英雄 一款由红帽公司原创的播客
You're listening to Command Line Heroes, an original podcast from Red Hat.
这是操作系统大战的第二部分：Linux 崛起
This is part two of the OS wars: Rise of Linux.
1998 年的时候 情况发生了变化
By 1998, things have changed.
Steven Vaughan-Nichols 是 zdnet.com 的特约编辑
Steven Vaughan-Nichols is a contributing editor at zdnet.com,
他已经写了几十年从商业方面论述技术的文章了
and he's been writing for decades about the business side of technology.
他将向我们讲述 Linux 是如何慢慢变得越来越流行
He describes how Linux slowly became more and more popular
直到自愿贡献者的数量远远超过了工作于 Windows 上的微软开发人员的数量
until the number of volunteer contributors was way larger than the number of Microsoft developers working on Windows.
不过 Linux 桌面版本从未真正追上 Windows
Linux never really went after Microsoft's desktop customers, though,
这也许就是微软最开始时忽略了 Linux 及其开发者的原因
and maybe that's why Microsoft ignored them at first.
Linux 真正大放光彩的地方是服务器机房
Where Linux did shine was in the server room.
当企业开始线上业务时
When businesses went online,
每个企业都需要一个满足其独特需求的解决方案
each one required a unique programming solution for their needs.
Windows NT 于 1993 年问世
Windows NT comes out in 1993
当时它已经在与其他的服务器操作系统展开竞争了
and it's competing with other server operating systems,
但是许多开发人员都在想
but lots of developers are thinking,
为什么我要傻乎乎地买 AIX 或者大型的 Windows 设备呢?
"Why am I going to buy an AIX box or a large windows box
我明明可以通过 Apache 来构建低成本的基于 linux 的系统
when I could set up a cheap Linux-based system with Apache?"
鉴于这个优点 Linux 代码已经开始渗透到几乎所有的在线机器中
Point is, Linux code started seeping into just about everything online.
让微软开始意识到并感到惊讶的是
Microsoft realizes that Linux, quite to their surprise,
Linux 实际上已经有了一些商业应用
is actually beginning to get some of the business,
不是在桌面环境 而是在商业服务器上
not so much on the desktop, but on business servers.
因此 他们发起了一场运动
As a result of that, they start a campaign,
我们称之为 FUD - 恐惧、不确定和怀疑
what we like to call FUD — fear, uncertainty and doubt
他们说 “哦 Linux 这玩意 真的没有那么好 它不太可靠 你根本不能相信它”
It's not very reliable. You can't trust it with anything."
这种软宣传式的攻击持续了一段时间
That soft propaganda style attack goes on for a while.
微软也不是唯一一个对 Linux 感到紧张的公司
Microsoft wasn't the only one getting nervous about Linux, either.
整个行业其实都在对抗这个奇怪新人的挑战
It was really a whole industry versus that weird new guy.
例如 任何与 UNIX 有利害关系的人都可能将 Linux 视为篡夺者
For example, anyone with a stake in UNIX was likely to see Linux as a usurper.
有一个案例很著名 那就是 SCO 组织,它发行过一种 UNIX 版本
Famously, the SCO Group, which had produced a version of UNIX,
在过去 10 多年里发起一系列的诉讼 试图阻止 Linux 的传播
waged lawsuits for over a decade to try and stop the spread of Linux.
而 SCO 最终失败而且破产了
SCO ultimately failed and went bankrupt.
与此同时 微软一直在寻找机会
Meanwhile, Microsoft kept searching for their opening.
他们必须要采取动作
They were a company that needed to make a move.
只是不清楚具体该怎么做
It just wasn't clear what that move was going to be.
第二年 真正让微软担心的事情发生了
What will make Microsoft really concerned about
在 2000 年的时候
it is the next year, in 2000,
IBM 宣布 他们将于 2001 年投资 10 亿美元在 Linux 上
IBM will announce that they will invest a billion dollars in Linux in 2001.
现在 IBM 已经不再涉足个人电脑业务
Now, IBM is not really in the PC business anymore.
那时他们还没有走出那一步 但他们正朝着这个方向前进
They're not out yet, but they're going in that direction,
他们将 Linux 视为服务器和大型计算机的未来
but what they are doing is they see Linux as being the future of servers and mainframe computers,
在这一点上 - 剧透警告 IBM 是正确的
which, spoiler alert, IBM was correct.
Linux 将主宰服务器世界
Linux is going to dominate the server world.
这已经不再仅仅是一群黑客所钟爱的
This was no longer just about a bunch of hackers loving their
对命令行绝地武士式的控制了
Jedi-like control of the command line.
事实上金钱的投入对 Linux 助力极大
This was about the money side working in Linux's favor in a major way.
程序员们着迷的这些东西恰好对大公司也极具吸引力
So the thing programmers are getting obsessed with also happens to be deeply attractive to big business.
但由于 FUD 的作用 一些企业对此持谨慎态度
Some businesses were wary. The FUD was having an effect.
他们听到开源 就想：“开源
They heard open source and thought, "Open.
这看起来不太可靠 很混乱 充满了 BUG”
That doesn't sound solid. It's going to be chaotic, full of bugs,"
但是金钱有一种有趣的魔力 可以说服人们不再踌躇
but money has a funny way of convincing people to get over their hangups.
甚至那些只需要网站的小公司也加入了 Linux 阵营
Even little businesses, all of which needed websites, were coming on board.
与一些昂贵的专有选择相比
The cost of working with a cheap Linux system over some expensive proprietary option,
使用 Linux 开销较低的优势显而易见
I mean there was really no comparison.
如果你是一家雇佣专业人员来构建网站的商店
there was really no comparison. If you were a shop hiring a pro to build your website,
那么你肯定想让他们使用 Linux
you wanted them to use Linux.
让我们快进几年
Fast forward a few years.
Linux 充当着几乎所有网站的服务器
Linux runs everybody's website.
Linux 已经征服了服务器世界
Linux has conquered the server world,
然后智能手机也随之诞生
and then, along comes the smartphone.
当然 苹果和他们的 iPhone 占据了相当大的市场份额
Apple and their iPhones take a sizeable share of the market,
而且微软也希望能进入这个市场
of course, and Microsoft hoped to get in on that,
但令人惊讶的是 Linux 已经等在那里并做好准备
except, surprise, Linux was there, too,
Linux也迫不及待要大展拳脚
ready and raring to go.
这是作家兼记者 James Allworth
Author and journalist James Allworth.
肯定还有容纳第二个竞争者的空间
There was certainly room for a second player,
那本可以是微软
and that could well have been Microsoft,
但是实际上却是 Android 而 Andrid 是基于 Linux 的
but for the fact of Android, which was fundamentally based on Linux,
众所周知 Android 被谷歌所收购
and because Android, famously acquired by Google,
现在运行在世界上大部分的智能手机上
and now running a majority of the world's smartphones,
谷歌在 Linux 的基础上创建了 Android
Google built it on top of that.
Linux 使他们能够以零成本 基于一个非常复杂的操作系统构建一个新的东西
They were able to start with a very sophisticated operating system and a cost basis of zero.
他们盘算着推广这个系统 并最终成功地实现了这一目标
They managed to pull it off, and it ended up
至少从操作系统的角度来看是这样 他们将微软挡在了下一代手机竞争之外
locking Microsoft out of the next generation of devices, by and large, at least from an operating system perspective.
为此 微软肯定对此感到非常紧张
So,they would right to be very worry about it.
这可是个大地震 很大程度上 微软有被埋没的风险
The ground was breaking up, big time, and Microsoft was in danger of falling into the cracks.
John Gossman 是微软 Azure 团队的首席架构师
John Gossman is the chief architect on the Azure team at Microsoft.
他还记得当时公司的迷茫
He remembers the confusion that gripped the company at that time.
像许多公司一样 微软也非常担心知识产权污染
Like a lot of companies, Microsoft was very concerned about IP pollution.
他们认为 如果允许开发人员使用开源代码
They thought that if you let developers use open source
即使只是将一些代码复制粘贴到某些产品中
they would likely just copy and paste bits of code into some product
也会让某种病毒式的许可证生效从而引发未知的风险…
and then some sort of a viral license might take effect that ...
他们也很困惑 我认为 这跟公司文化有关
And they were also very confused, I think, it was just culturally,
很多公司 包括微软
a lot of companies, Microsoft included,
对开源开发的意义和商业模式之间的分歧感到困惑
were confused on the difference between what open source development meant and what the business model was.
有一种观点认为 开源意味着你所有的软件都是免费的 人们永远不会付钱
This is kind of idea that open source meant that all your software was free and people were never going to pay anything.
任何习惯于投资于旧的、专有软件模式的人
Anybody invested in the old, proprietary model of software
都会觉得这里发生的一切对他们构成了威胁
is going to feel threatened by what's happening here.
当你威胁到像微软这样的大公司时
When you threaten an enormous company like Microsoft,
是的 他们一定会做出反应
Yeah, you can bet they're going to react.
他们推动所有这些 FUD
It makes sense they were pushing all that FUD —
恐惧、不确定性和怀疑
fear, uncertainty and doubt.
当时 商业运作的方式基本上就是相互竞争
At the time, an “ us versus them ” attitude was pretty much how business worked.
不过 如果是其他公司的话
If they'd been any other company, though,
他们可能还会一直怀恨在心 抱残守缺
they might have kept that old grudge, that old thinking,
但到了 2013 年的微软 一切都变了
but then, in 2013, everything changes.
微软的云计算服务 Azure 上线了
Microsoft's cloud computing service, Azure, goes online
令人震惊的是 它从第一天开始就提供了 Linux 虚拟机
and, shockingly, it offers Linux virtual machines from day one.
史蒂夫·鲍尔默,这位把 Linux 称为癌症的首席执行官
Steve Ballmer, the CEO who called Linux a cancer,
已经离开了
he's out,
代替他的是一位新的有远见的首席执行官 - 萨提亚·纳德拉
and a new forward - thinking CEO, Satya Nadella, has been brought in.
萨提亚有不同的看法
Satya has a different attitude.
他属于另一个世代,比保罗、比尔和史蒂夫更年轻的世代
He's another generation. He's a generation younger than Paul and Bill and Steve were,
他对开源有不同的看法
and had a different perspective on open source.
这是 John Gossman 他还是来自微软 Azure 团队
John Gossman, again, from Microsoft's Azure team.
大约四年前 我们在 Azure 中添加了 Linux 支持
We added Linux support into Azure about four years ago,
迫于求生欲
and that was for very pragmatic reasons.
如果访问任何一家企业客户
If you go to any enterprise customer,
你都会发现
you will find that
他们并不是现在才决定是用 Windows 还是 Linux
they are not trying to decide whether to use Windows to use Linux
或是用 .NET 还是 Java
or to use Linux
他们在很久以前就做出了决定 - 大约 15 年前
They made all those decisions a long time ago — about 15 years or so ago,
虽然对此有一些争论
there was some of this argument.
现在 我见过的每一家公司都混合了
Now, every company that I have ever seen has a mix of
Linux 和 Java、Windows 和 .NET、
Linux and Java and Windows and .NET
SQL Server、Oracle 和 MySQL 等
and SQL Server and Oracle and MySQL
这些基于专有源代码的产品和开放源代码的产品
— proprietary source code - based products and open source code products.
如果你打算运维一个云服务
And if you're going to operate a cloud
允许这些公司在云上运行他们的业务
you're going to allow and enable those companies to run their businesses on the cloud,
那么你根本不能告诉他们
you simply cannot tell them,
“你可以使用这个软件 不能使用那个软件 ”
"You can use this software but you can't use this software."
这正是萨提亚·纳德拉采纳的哲学思想
That's exactly the philosophy that Satya Nadella adopted.
2014 年秋季 他站在舞台上
In the fall of 2014, he gets up on stage
希望传递一个重要信息
and he wants to get across one big, fat point.
“微软爱 Linux”
Microsoft loves Linux.
他接着说 “20% 的 Azure 业务已经是 Linux 了
He goes on to say that 20 % of Azure is already Linux
微软将始终对 Linux 发行版提供一流的支持”
and that Microsoft will always have first - class support for Linux distros.
没有哪怕一丝对开源的宿怨
There's not even a whiff of that old antagonism toward open source.
为了说明这一点
To drive the point home,
在他们的背后有一个巨大的标志 上面写着：
there's literally a giant sign behind them that reads,
“Microsoft ❤️ Linux”
"Microsoft hearts Linux."
噢 对我们中的一些人来说 这种转变有点令人震惊
Aww. For some of us, that turnaround was a bit of a shock,
但实际上 无需如此震惊
but really, it shouldn't have been.
下面是 Steven Levy 一名科技记者兼作家
Here's Steven Levy, a tech journalist and author.
当你在踢足球的时候 如果草坪变滑了
When you're playing a football game and the turf becomes really slick,
换种不同的鞋子 才能继续在上面玩耍
maybe you switch to a different kind of footwear in order to play on that turf.
微软当初就是这么做的
That's what they were doing.
他们不能否认现实 而且他们也是聪明人
They can't deny reality and there are smart people there
所以他们必须意识到 这就是这个世界的运行方式
so they had to realize that this is the way the world is and put aside what they said earlier,
即使他们有一点尴尬
even though they might be a little embarrassed
但是不管他们早些时候说了什么现在都要抛开
at their earlier statements,
不然让他们之前那些“开源多么可怕”的言论影响到现在的决策
but it would be crazy to let their statements about how horrible open source was earlier,
才真的是不明智之举
affect their smart decisions now.
微软低下了它高傲的头
Microsoft swallowed its pride in a big way.
你可能还记得苹果公司
You might remember that Apple,
经过多年的孤立无援 最终转向与微软构建合作伙伴关系
after years of splendid isolation, finally shifted toward a partnership with Microsoft.
现在轮到微软进行 180 度转变了
Well,Now it was Microsoft's turn to do a 180.
经过多年的与开源方式的战斗后
After years of battling the open source approach,
他们正在重塑自己
they were reinventing themselves.
要么改变 要么死亡
It was change or perish.
下一个发言的是 Steven Vaughan-Nichols
Steven Vaughan-Nichols.
即使是像微软这样规模的公司
Even a company the size of Microsoft
也无法与数千个开发着包括 Linux 在内的各类开源大项目的开发者竞争
simply can't compete with the thousands of open source developers working on all these other major projects, including Linux.
很长时间以来他们都不愿意合作
They were very loath e to do so for a long time.
前微软首席执行官史蒂夫·鲍尔默对 Linux 用接近信仰的方式深恶痛绝
The former Microsoft CEO, Steve Ballmer, hated Linux with a passion.
由于它使用的 GPL 许可证 他视 Linux 为一种癌症
Because of its GPL license, it was a cancer,
不过一旦鲍尔默被扫地出门
but once Ballmer was finally shown the door,
新的微软领导层表示
the new Microsoft leadership said,
“这就好像试图命令潮流不要过来
"This is like trying to order the tide to stop coming in.
但潮水依然会不断涌进来
The tide is going to keep coming in.
我们应该与 Linux 合作 而不是与之对抗 ”
We should work with Linux, not against it."
说真的 线上技术史中最大的胜利之一
Really, one of the big wins of the history of online techs
就是微软终于做出这个改变 而且还成功了
is the way Microsoft was able to make this pivit when they finally decided to.
当然 Linux 的老支持者对微软支持开源一事仍持怀疑态度
Of course, older hard core Linux supporters were pretty sceptical when Microsoft showed up at the open source table.
他们不确定能不能欢迎这些家伙
They weren't sure if they can embrace these guys.
但正如 Vaughan-Nichols 所说
But, as Vaughan-Nichols  points out,
如今的微软已不再是上一辈人所见的微软了
today's Microsoft simply is not your mom and dad's Microsoft.
2017 年的微软既不是史蒂夫·鲍尔默的微软
Microsoft 2017 is not Steve Ballffmer's Microsoft,
也不是比尔·盖茨的微软
nor is it Bill Gates' Microsoft.
这是一家完全不同的公司 有着完全不同的理念
It's an entirely different company with a very different approach
而且 一旦使用了开源 你就无法退回到之前的阶段
and, again, once you start using open source, it's not like you can really pull back.
开源已经吞噬了整个技术世界
For that matter, Open source has devoured the entire technology world.
从未听说过 Linux 的人可能对它并不了解
People who have never heard of Linux as such, don't know it,
但是每次他们访问 Facebook 他们都在运行 Linux
but every time they're on Facebook, they're running Linux.
每次执行谷歌搜索时 你都在运行 Linux
Every time you do a Google search, you're running Linux.
每次你用 Android 手机 你都在运行 Linux
Every time you do anything with your Android phone, you're running Linux again.
事实上它早已无处不在
It literally is everywhere,
微软无法阻止它
and Microsoft can't stop that,
而且我认为 以为微软想用某种方式接管它的想法太天真了
and thinking that Microsoft can somehow take it all over, I think is naïve.
开源支持者可能一直担心微软会像混入羊群中的狼一样
So Open source supporters might have been worrying about Microsoft coming in like a wolf in the flock,
但事实是 开源软件的本质保护了它 让它无法被完全控制
but the truth is, the very nature of open source software protects it from total domination.
没有一家公司能够拥有 Linux 并以某种特定的方式控制它
No single company can own Linux and control it in any specific way.
Greg Kroah-Hartman 是 Linux 基金会的一名成员
Greg Kroah-Hartman is a fellow at the Linux Foundation.
每个公司和个人都因为自己的利益对 Linux 做出贡献
Every company and every individual contributes to Linux in a selfish manner.
他们之所以这样做是因为他们想要解决他们所面临的问题
They're doing so because they want to solve a problem that they have,
可能是硬件无法工作 或者是他们想要添加一个新功能来做其他事情
be it hardware isn't working , or they want to add a new feature to do something else,
又或者想引导 Linux 的开发轨道 这样他们的新产品就能使用它
or want to take it in a direction that they'll build that they can use for their product.
这很棒 因为他们会把代码贡献回去 此后每个人都会从中受益
That's great, because then everybody benefits from that because they're releasing the code back,
这样每个人都可以用到这份代码
so everybody can use it.
正是因为这种自私 所有的公司 所有的人都能从中受益
So,It's because of that selfishness that all companies and all people have, everybody benefits.
微软已经意识到 在即将到来的云战争中
Microsoft has realized that in the coming cloud wars,
与 Linux 对抗就好比与空气斗智斗勇
fighting Linux would be like going to war with, well, a cloud.
Linux 和开源不是敌人 它们是空气
Linux and open source aren't the enemy, they're the atmosphere.
如今 微软以白金会员的身份加入了 Linux 基金会
Today, Microsoft has joined the Linux Foundation as a platinum member.
他们成为 GitHub 开源项目的头号贡献者
They became the number one contributor to open source on GitHub.
2017 年 9 月 他们甚至加入了开源促进联盟（OSI）
In September, 2017, they even joined the Open Source Initiative.
现在 微软在开源许可证下发布了很多代码
These days, Microsoft releases a lot of its code under open licenses.
微软的 John Gossman 描述了他们开源 .NET 时所发生的事情
Microsoft's John Gossman describes what happened when they open sourced .NET.
起初 他们并不认为自己能得到什么回报
At first, they didn't really think they'd get much back.
我们本没有指望来自社区的贡献
We didn't count on contributions from the community,
然而 三年后 超过 50% 的对 .NET 框架库的贡献来自于微软之外
and yet, three years in, over 50 per cent of the contributions to the .NET framework libraries, now, are coming from outside of Microsoft.
这些是大量的代码
This includes big pieces of code.
三星为 .NET 提供了 ARM 支持
Samsung has contributed ARM support to .NET.
Intel 和 ARM 以及其他一些芯片厂商
Intel and ARM and a couple other chip
已经为 .NET 框架贡献了特定于他们处理器的代码
people have contributed code generation specific for their processors to the .NET framework,
以及数量惊人的修复 bug、性能改进等等
as well as a surprising number of fixes, performance improvements , and stuff
既有单个贡献者也有社区
- from just individual contributors to the community.
直到几年前 今天的这个微软
Up until a few years ago, the Microsoft we have today,
这个开放的微软 还是不可想象的
this open Microsoft, would have been unthinkable.
我是 Saron Yitbarek 这里是代码英雄
I'm Saron Yitbarek, and this is Command Line Heroes.
好吧 我们已经看到了为了赢得数百万桌面用户的爱而战的激烈场面
Okay, we've seen titanic battles for the love of millions of desktop users.
我们已经看到开源软件在专有软件巨头的背后悄然崛起
We've seen open source software creep up
并攫取了巨大的市场份额
behind the proprietary titans, and nab huge market share.
我们已经看到了一批批的代码英雄
We've seen fleets of command line heroes
将编程领域变成了我你今天看到的这个样子
transform the programming landscape into the one handed down to people like me and you.
如今 大企业正在吸收开源软件
Today, big business is absorbing open source software,
通过这一切 每个人都从他人那里受益
and through it all, everybody is still borrowing from everybody.
在技术的西部荒野 一贯如此
In the tech wild west, it's always been that way.
苹果受到施乐（Xerox）的启发 微软受到苹果的启发
Apple gets inspired by Xerox, Microsoft gets inspired by Apple,
Linux 受到 UNIX 的启发
Linux gets inspired by UNIX.
进化、借鉴、不断成长
Evolve, borrow, constantly grow.
如果比喻成大卫和歌利亚的话 开源软件不再是大卫
In David and Goliath terms, open source software is no longer a David,
但是 你知道吗？它也不是歌利亚
but, you know what? It's not even Goliath, either.
开源已经超越了这些角色
Open source has transcended.
它成为了其他人战斗的战场
It's become the battlefield that others fight on.
随着开源变得不可避免
So the open source approach becomes inevitable,
新的战争
new wars,
那些在云计算中进行的战争
wars that are fought in the cloud,
那些在开源战场上进行的战争正在加剧
wars that are fought on the open source battlefield, are ramping up.
这是 Steven Levy 他是一名作者
Here's author Steven Levy.
基本上 到目前为止
Basically, right now,
基本上 到目前为止 包括微软在内 有四到五家公司
Basically, right now, we have four or five companies, if you count Microsoft,
正以各种方式
they in various ways
努力把自己打造成为全方位的平台 比如人工智能领域
are fighting to be the platform for all we do, for artificial intelligence, say.
你能看到智能助手之间的战争 你猜怎么着？
You see wars between intelligent assistants, and guess what?
苹果有一个智能助手 叫 Siri
Apple has an intelligent assistant, Siri.
微软有一个 叫 Cortana
Microsoft has one, Cortana.
谷歌有谷歌助手
Google has the Google Assistant.
三星也有一个智能助手
Samsung has an intelligent assistant.
亚马逊也有一个 叫 Alexa
Amazon has one, Alexa.
我们看到这些战斗遍布各地
We see these battles shifting to different areas, there.
也许 你可以说 最热门的人工智能平台
Maybe, you could say, the hottest one is would be, whose AI platform
将控制我们生活中所有的东西
is going to control all the stuff in our lives there,
而这五家公司就是在为此而争斗
and those five companies are all competing for that.
如果你正在寻找另一个反叛者
If you're looking for another rebel
它们就像 Linux 奇袭微软那样
that's going to sneak up behind Facebook or
偷偷躲在 Facebook、谷歌或亚马逊身后
Google or Amazon and blindside them the way Linux blindsided Microsoft,
你也许要等很久 因为正如作家 James Allworth 所指出的
you might be looking a long time, because as author James Allworth points out,
成为一个真正的反叛者只会变得越来越难
being a true rebel is only getting harder and harder.
规模一直以来都是一种优势 但规模优势本质上…
Scale's always been an advantage but the nature of scale advantages are almost ...
怎么说呢 我认为以前它们在本质上是线性的
Whereas, I think previously they were more linear in nature,
现在它们在本质上是指数型的了
now it's more exponential in nature,
所以 一旦你开始以某种方法走在前面
and so, once you start to get out in front with something like this ,
另一个新玩家要想赶上来就变得越来越难了
it becomes harder and harder for a new player to come in and catch up.
我认为在互联网时代这大体来说来说是正确的
I think this is true of the internet era in general,
无论是因为规模 还是数据赋予组织的竞争力的重要性和优势
whether it's scale like that or the importance and advantages that data bestow on an organization in terms of its ability to compete.
一旦你走在前面 你就会吸引更多的客户
Once you get out in front, you attract more customers,
这就给了你更多的数据 让你能做得更好
and then that gives you more data and that enables you to do an even better job,
这之后 客户还有什么理由选择排名第二的公司呢
and then, why on earth would you want to go with the number two player,
难道是因为因为他们落后了这么远么？
because they're so far behind?
我认为在云的时代这个逻辑也不会有什么不同
I think it's going to be no different in cloud.
这个故事始于史蒂夫·乔布斯和比尔·盖茨这样的非凡的英雄
This story began with singular heroes like Steve Jobs and Bill Gates,
但科技的进步已经呈现出一种众包、自有生命的感觉
but the progress of technology has taken on a crowdsourced, organic feel.
我认为据说我们的开源英雄林纳斯·托瓦兹
I think it's telling that our open source hero, Linus Torvalds,
在第一次发明 Linux 内核时甚至没有一个真正的计划
didn't even have a real plan when he first invented the Linux kernel.
他无疑是一位才华横溢的年轻开发者
He was a brilliant, young developer for sure,
但他也像潮汐前的一滴水一样
but he was also like a single drop of water at the very front of a tidal wave.
变革是不可避免的
The revolution was inevitable.
据估计 对于一家专有软件公司来说
It's been estimated that for a proprietary company to create
用他们老式的、专有的方式创建一个 Linux 发行版
a Linux distribution in their old - fashioned, proprietary way,
将花费他们超过 100 亿美元
it would cost them well over $10 billion.
这说明了开源的力量
That points to the power of open source.
最后 这并不是一个专有模型所能与之竞争的东西
In the end, it's not something that a proprietary model is going to compete with.
成功的公司必须保持开放
Successful companies have to remain open.
这是最大、最终极的教训
That's the big, ultimate lesson in all this.
还有一点要记住：当我们团结在一起的时候
Something else to keep in mind: When we're wired together,
我们在已有基础上成长和建设的能力是无限的
our capacity to grow and build on what we've already accomplished becomes limitless.
不管这些公司有多大 我们都不必坐等他们给我们更好的东西
As big as these companies get, we don't have to sit around waiting for them to give us something better.
想想那些为了纯粹的创造乐趣而学习编码的新开发者
Think about the new developer who learns to code for the sheer joy of creating,
那些自己动手丰衣足食的人
the mom who decides that if nobody's going to build what she needs, then she'll build it herself.
未来的优秀程序员不论来自何方
Wherever tomorrow's great programmers come from,
只要能够访问代码 他们就能构建下一个大项目
they're always going to have the capacity to build the next big thing, so long as there's access to the command line.
以上就是我们关于操作系统战争的故事
That's it for our two - part tale on the OS wars
这场战争塑造了我们的数字生活的形态
that shaped our digital lives.
争夺主导地位的斗争从桌面转移到了服务器机房
The struggle for dominance moved from the desktop to the server room,
最终进入了云计算领域
and ultimately into the cloud.
过去的敌人难以置信地变成了盟友
Old enemies became unlikely allies,
众包的未来让一切都变得开放
and a crowdsourced future left everything open.
听着 我知道 在这段历史之旅中 还有很多英雄我们没有提到
Listen, I know, there are a hundred other heroes we didn't have space for in this history trip,
所以给我们写信吧 分享你的故事 我恭候佳音
so drop us a line. Share your story. Redhat.com/commandlineheroes. I'm listening.
在本季剩下的时间里 我们将学习今天的英雄们在创造什么
We're spending the rest of the season learning what today's heroes are creating,
以及他们要经历什么样的战斗才能将他们的创造物带入我们的生活
and what battles they're going through to bring their creations to life.
让我们从壮丽的编程一线 回来看看更多的传奇故事吧
Come back for more tales — from the epic front lines of programming.
我们每两周放一集新的播客
We drop a new episode every two weeks.
几周后 我们将为你带来第三集：敏捷革命
In a couple weeks' time, we bring you episode three: the Agile Revolution.
代码英雄是一款红帽公司原创的播客
Command Line Heroes is an original podcast from Red Hat.
这里是 Saron Yitbarek 感谢收听 请继续编程
I'm Saron Yitbarek. Thanks for listening. Keep on coding.